Eric Hussman

Full Stack Developer

503.819.4820 eric.hussmann@gmail.com

erichussmann.com • github.com/erihus • linkedin.com/in/erichussmann

I am a skilled developer and solutions engineer with a broad range of skills. Best described as a T-shaped generalist, I specialize primarily in building web-based software applications, but my varied experiences have given me the opportunity learn and utilize many different skills to bring value to organizations of all sizes. My ability to identify or develop the right technology solution for the task has been crucial to my success. I am constantly studying to learn a new language or framework, stay up-to-date on the latest tools and trends, and push my comfort zone. I love creating unique solutions and working with teams that are passionate, motivated and full of ideas.

Skills

Backend

PHP, Laravel, Python, Flask, Wordpress, Node.js, MySQL, Linux, Apache, nginx, REST APIs, Docker, cloud virtualization

Frontend

Javascript, React, Redux, Angular, Backbone, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS & LESS

Tooling

git, gulp, browserify, webpack, composer, npm, pip, apt, curl, wget, rsync, scp, tar, vi, VS Code, Sublime, PyCharm, Postman

Testing

Jest, enzyme, mocha, chai, phpunit, behat

Experience

ASML / Software Engineer

November 2018 - Present, HILLSBORO, OR

I joined ASML to be part of an exciting internal software development team with the goal of delivering a custom planning tool for the deployment and maintenance of next generation semiconductor lithography machines.

- Work across the technology stack (nginx, Mysql, Python/Flask, external data APIs, React/Redux) to deliver the most value where needed on a small, Agile team
- Key voice in daily Scrums and bi-weekly Sprint retrospectives/planning. Actively help the team refine their Agile process. Digest and forecast user stories. Coordinate technical implementation.
- Work closely with developers and product owners on the team and across the organization to find creative, robust solutions for complex domain requirements.
- Responsible for key deliverables in a fast-paced environment to deliver MVP software on an aggressive timeline.

Vogey, Inc / Senior Solutions Architect

JUNE 2015 - December 2018, PORTLAND, OR

Provided technology solutions and full-stack development for Vogey's diverse array of clientele and project scopes.

- Help discover client business processes and workflows
- Identify or develop technology solutions to build efficiencies
- Help grow lines of business by researching solutions for new vertical markets
- Manage all servers and codebases for client technology

M Financial / Technology Solutions Consultant

JUNE 2015 - December 2018, PORTLAND, OR

As part of Vogey, Inc.'s team embedded at M Financial, I have overseen the technical implementation of key organization-wide projects. Vogey provides website vendor service to over 100 M Financial Member Firm organizations and administers M's internal ticketing software.

- Engineered and actively maintain a highly available cloud-based Linux hosting platform for the website program
- Developed a multi-concept, highly configurable Wordpress theme and several plugins to furnish firms with modern, unique and cost-effective websites and tools to streamline their compliance and support workflows
- Key member in the design and implementation of M's new enterprise help-desk software (Zendesk), including development of custom workflow apps and integrations with other systems for regulatory compliance and books and records.
- Provided consultation and development for M's marketing and communications team, helping them modernize their marketing materials with web-based tools and micro-sites.

Freelance / Web & App Developer

JUNE 2015 - DECEMBER 2018, PORTLAND, OR

- Provided timely, bug-free code deliverables for a wide variety of local and national clients, including Fetzer Wines, Baskin Robbins, PolarTec, La Tortilla, Frank Creative, Blanchet House and more.
- Provided clients with clear timelines and estimates based on thorough requirements gathering.

Harlo Interactive / Lead Developer

MARCH 2012 - JUNE 2015, PORTLAND, OR

❖ Lead developer on a wide variety of web projects, including e-commerce, front end, API and database development, and custom CMS solutions.

- Developed a proprietary CMS on Laravel 5 and Angular. Modular architecture allows fast creation of purpose-built solutions with minimal coding.
- Specialized in creating interactive applications to suit client needs.
- Provide consultation on strategy, timeline forecasting, resource management, and technical delivery.
- Managed dev team operations, including version control, code reviews, test driven development and upgrades to our technology stack and build tools.

MediaLab, Inc. / Lead Technical Support Engineer

MARCH 2008 - MAY 2012, PORTLAND, OR

- Provided high level support for issues related to Web development software.
- Required expert knowledge of HTML and CSS, as well as fluency in PHP, Wordpress, Javascript/AJAX and Photoshop.
- ❖ Integrated InfusionSoft CRM and Zendesk APIs to create revenue generating paid support levels within Zendesk.
- ❖ Developed standards-compliant, cross-browser HTML and CSS models for use by the software for web page generation.
- Responsible for updating and maintaining company Website. Implemented SEO and analytics solutions to increase site usability and improve revenue generation.
- Supported customer education with sample files, documentation and live webinar demonstrations

Education

University of California, Santa Cruz / B.A., Modern Literary Studies 2005, SANTA CRUZ, CA